Guide to the Stuyvesant-Rutherfurd Papers 1647-1917 (bulk 1840-1917) MS 605
New-York Historical Society
- Series XV: Lewis Morris Rutherfurd
  - Lewis Morris Rutherfurd: Other Subseries
    - Lewis Morris Rutherfurd -- Century Association Annual Election, 1879 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Lewis Morris Rutherfurd -- Articles, 1865, 1872 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Lewis Morris Rutherfurd -- Obituary, 1892 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Lewis Morris Rutherfurd -- List of Items from Will, [1887] (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Mr. [Lewis Morris] Rutherfurd -- Hair Cutting, 1891 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Series XVI: Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd
  Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd was the wife of Lewis Morris Rutherfurd. In addition to the subseries described below, the series includes some school notebooks, mostly dealing with the history of the ancient Near East.
  - Subseries 1: Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd - Letters Received N.D., 1858-1890
    There is little material in this subseries dating from before 1871, and very little material from the years 1874-1884. Most of the correspondence is from Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd, husband, Lewis Morris Rutherfurd, and from her children, particularly Rutherfurd Stuyvesant and Margaret Rutherfurd White.
    Subjects include Lewis Morris Rutherfurd's account of a trip to Great Britain in 1871, including his observations on ladies' fashions of the day. During her European tour with her husband in 1873, Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd received numerous letters, particularly from Rutherfurd Stuyvesant, concerning family and social affairs in New York. In the summer of 1884, he writes to her about his experiences on a hunting trip to Montana and Wyoming. Letters from her daughter Margaret Rutherfurd White in 1890 describe social events and the Whites' acquaintance with prominent persons in London.
    - Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd -- Letters Received, N.D., 1858 - 1872 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd -- Letters Received, 1873 - 1888 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd -- Letters Received, 1889 1890 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 2: Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd - Letters to Her Children N.D., 1864-1866
    Some of the undated letters appear to have been written when Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd was caring for the children's dying grandmother, apparently Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd's own mother. Other letters appear to have been written to her adult children as they traveled as a party in Europe.
    - Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd -- Letters to Her Children, N.D., 1864 -1866 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 3: Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd - Accounts, Bills, Receipts N.D., 1865-1889
    From business in Europe and New York, for household such as silverware, rugs, lamps, items, fabrics, etc. Some receipts are for her contributions to charities, such as the Society for the Relief of Poor Widows with Small Children.
    - Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts, N.D., 1865 - June 1886 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts, July 1886 - April 1888 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts, May 1888 - 1889 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd: Other Subseries
    - Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd -- School Notebooks, N.D. (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Series XVII: Louisa M. Rutherfurd (1859-1892)
  Louisa M. Rutherfurd was the daughter of Lewis Morris Rutherfurd and Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd. The series includes some notes written by or to Louisa M. Rutherfurd, including two, in French, written on the leaves of a tree or bush.
  - Subseries 1: Louisa M. Rutherfurd - Letters Received N.D., 1872-1881, 1890
    The most frequent correspondents are Margaret Rutherfurd White and Louisa M. Rutherfurd's friend "Mattie", probably Matilda Amelia Barreda. For the most part, Margaret Rutherfurd White addressed Louisa M. Rutherfurd as "Poodle". "Mattie" addressed her as "Duckie." Usually, correspondents (including, on occasion, Margaret Rutherfurd White) addressed Louisa M. Rutherfurd as "Loulou."
    Subjects are primarily social and family news. Matilda Amelia Barreda's letters include several from San Francisco in 1878-1879, wherein she writes about her homesickness and the manners of the nouveaux riches of that city. Margaret Rutherfurd White writes frequently from Europe, where her husband served as a diplomat. She writes about society and her experiences in France and Great Britain. She frequently mentions prominent persons she has met, for example, in 1878, Secretary for Ireland (later Prime Minister) Arthur Balfour. In 1890, she writes from Windsor Castle describing a dinner with Queen Victoria which she and her husband, Henry White, attended on December of that year.
    - Louisa M. Rutherfurd (1859 - 1892) -- Letters Received, N.D. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Louisa M. Rutherfurd (1859 - 1892) -- Letters Received, 1872 - 1877 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Louisa M. Rutherfurd (1859 - 1892) -- Letters Received, 1878 - 1881, 1890 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Louisa M. Rutherfurd: Other Subseries
    - Louisa M. Rutherfurd (1859 - 1892) -- Notes, N.D., 1872, 1874 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Miss L. M. Rutherfurd [1859 - 1892] -- List of Property, N.D. (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Series XVIII: Margaret Rutherfurd White
  Margaret Rutherfurd White was the daughter of Lewis Morris Rutherfurd and Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd. She married Henry White, a U.S. diplomat, in 1879. The series consists of letters that she received, and a small number of receipts and bills.
  - Subseries 1: Margaret Rutherfurd White - Letters Received N.D., 1873-1893
    Most of the correspondence is from Margaret Rutherfurd White's sister-in-law, Margaret Rutherfurd Stuyvesant. Other correspondents include Margaret Rutherfurd White's mother, Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd, and her cousin, Mary E. Pierrepont. Content mainly deals with family and social matters, including Louisa M. Rutherfurd's illness and confinement to a sanatorium in the early 1890's.
    - Margaret Rutherfurd White -- Letters Received, N.D., 1873 - 1893 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 2: Margaret Rutherfurd White - Accounts, Bills, Receipts N.D., 1881, 1887-1888
    Most of the material is from the Army and Navy Cooperative Society, Ltd., London, from which Mrs. White purchased items such as furniture and drapery.
    - Margaret Rutherfurd White -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts, N.D., 1881, 1887 - 1888 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Series XIX: Rutherfurd Family
  This series contains small amounts of material relating to specific members of the Rutherfurd Family, as well as items that cannot be identified with a specific person. The series includes letters to, among other persons, John Rutherfurd, Walter Rutherfurd, and Sabina Morris Rutherfurd.
  Material relating to John Rutherfurd includes accounts and legal documents relating to the estate of William Jauncey, and to the Bellville Bridge and Turnpike Association.
  Items relating to Walter Rutherfurd include accounts from the Royal American Regiment, and enlistment papers of soldiers in that regiment.
  The letters to Sabina Morris Rutherfurd appear to have been originally bound together. These items have been left in what appears to be their original order. Most of the letters are from her son and daughter-in-law, Lewis Morris Rutherfurd and Margaret Chanler Rutherfurd. The letters were for the most part sent from Europe in 1849-1850. The subject matter of the letters deals with the experiences and progress of the traveling party, and the unstable political situation in Europe at the time.
  - Rutherfurd Family -- John Rutherfurd -- Letters Received, N.D., 1796 - 1799, 1808 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- John Rutherfurd (And estate of -) -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts, N.D., 1793 - 1815, 1840 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- John Rutherfurd -- Legal Papers, 1808 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- John Rutherfurd -- Advertisement for Auction, 1806 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- John Rutherfurd -- Schedule of Abstracts of Deeds, 1802 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- John Rutherfurd -- Estate of William Jauncey, 1833 - 1834 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- John Rutherfurd -- Bellville Bridge & Turnpike Association, 1831 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- John Rutherfurd -- Will and Legal Opinion re Will, 1840 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- John and Mary Rutherfurd -- Letters received (Bound), 1806 - 1808 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Walter Rutherfurd -- Letters Received, 1758 - 1796 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Walter Rutherfurd -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1757 - 1801 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Walter Rutherfurd -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts -- Account Book, 1795 - 1797 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Walter Rutherfurd -- Legal Papers, 1763 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Walter Rutherfurd -- Royal American Regiment -- Enlistments, 1757, 1758 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Walter Rutherfurd -- Royal American Regiment -- Accounts, 1758 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Major John Rutherfurd (d. 1758) -- Account, 1756 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Sabina Morris Rutherfurd -- Letters Received, N.D., 1849 - 1851 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- [Catherine Alexander Rutherfurd] -- Letters Received, [1758] (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Catherine Alexander Rutherfurd -- Account (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Catherine Alexander Rutherfurd -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts -- Account Book, 1789 - 1792 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- John Rutherfurd Jr. - - Letters Received, 1829 - 1840 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Lewis Morris Rutherfurd [Jr.] -- Letter Sent to His Sister, 1873 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Louisa Morris Rutherfurd (1792 - 1857) -- Letters Sent, Recipients Unknown, 1850 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Miss [Louisa Morris] Rutherfurd (1792 - 1857) -- Receipt, 1809 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Miss [Louisa Morris] Rutherfurd (1792 - 1857) -- Invitations to La Fayette Ball, 1824 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Mary Rutherfurd -- Legal Papers, 1840 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Walter Rutherfurd (1812 - 1868) -- Letters Received, 1864 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Walter Rutherfurd (1812 - 1868) -- Account, 1864 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- [Winthrop Rutherfurd] -- Letter Received, 1873 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Winthrop Rutherfurd -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1887 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- William O. Rutherfurd -- Letter Received, 1866 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Miss [ ] Rutherfurd -- Letters Received, N.D., 1842 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Miss [ ] Rutherfurd -- Receipts, N.D., 1801 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Mr. [ ] Rutherfurd -- Letter Received, 1893 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Mr. [ ] Rutherfurd -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts, N.D., 1777 - 1820 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Mrs. [ ] Rutherfurd -- Letters Received, [1796], 1865 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Mrs. [ ] Rutherfurd -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts, N.D. 1797 - 1817 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Mrs. [ ] Rutherfurd -- Account Book, 1884 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Inventories, 1878, 1897, 1901 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Legal Papers, 1778 - 1798 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Surveys, N.D. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- Tracing of Third Story of House at Tranquillity, N.D. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Rutherfurd Family -- weights and Ages of Children of Rutherfurd and Related Families, 1819 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Rutherfurd Family/White Family -- Contracts for Home Nurses, 1886 - 1887 (Box 20, Folder 13)
- Series XX: Alexander Family
  This series consists of material created by or pertaining to James Alexander, Mary Alexander, and William Alexander.
  - Alexander Family -- James Alexander -- Letters Received, N.D.,1725 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Alexander Family -- James Alexander -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1736 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Alexander Family -- James Alexander -- Court Papers, 1727 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Alexander Family -- [Estate of James Alexander] -- Legal Papers, 1755 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Alexander Family -- Mary Alexander -- Letters Received, 1736 - 1758 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Alexander Family -- Mary Alexander -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1755 - 1759 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Alexander Family -- Mary Alexander -- Legal Papers, 1758 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Alexander Family -- William Alexander -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1747 - 1754 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Alexander Family -- William Alexander -- Copy of Order of Gen. Shirley, 1755 (Box 20, Folder 22)
- Series XXI: Other Persons N.D., 1714-1931
  This series consists of correspondence and papers of persons who were not members of the Rutherfurd or Stuyvesant families, members of the European branches of those families or persons who cannot be identified. The series includes letters sent by members of the Rutherfurd or Stuyvesant families to these persons, and correspondence between these persons. The series includes five letters (1812-1813) by John Jay to Peter Augustus Jay, discussing, among other things, politics.
  - Other Persons -- Theodore Ayers -- Letters Received, 1889 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Other Persons -- George Blydenburgh -- Letters Received, 1917 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Other Persons -- Capt. [ ] Bryant -- Letters Received, N.D. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Other Persons -- St. Clare Byrne -- Letters Received, 1895 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Other Persons -- Baron [] de Carron -- Letters Received, 1893 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Other Persons -- Louis Stuyvesant Chanler -- Letters Received, 1900 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Other Persons -- Gen. [Mathew] Clarkson -- Letters Received, 1792, 1796 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Other Persons -- Rev. Dr. [ ] Cooper -- Letters Received, N.D. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Other Persons -- Mme. [ ] Crele -- Postcarrd Received, 1908 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Other Persons -- Arthur Danks -- Letters Received, 1908 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Other Persons -- Miss [ ] Dongan -- Letters Received, 1888 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Other Persons -- Miss [ ] Duggan -- Letters Received, 1887, 1888 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Other Persons -- Mrs. [ ] Duggan -- Letters Received, 1887 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Other Persons -- James Ewing -- Letters Received, 1840, 1842 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Other Persons -- H. C. Fahnestock -- Letters Received, 1904 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Other Persons -- Mr. Hanks -- Letters Received, 1888 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Other Persons -- C. H. Higginson -- Letters Received, 1869 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Other Persons -- H. S. Howard -- Letters Received, 1895 - 1896 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Other Persons -- S. B. Jameson -- Letters Received, 1893, 1901, 1906 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Other Persons -- John C. Jay -- Letters Received, 1842 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Other Persons -- Mary Clarkson Jay -- Letters Received, N.D., 1800, 1837 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Other Persons -- Peter Augustus Jay -- Letters Received, 1809, 1812, 1813 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Other Persons -- Peter van Brugh Livingston -- Letters Received, 1744 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Other Persons -- Miss [ ] Marshall -- Letters Received, 1883 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Other Persons -- Morris & Steele -- Letters Received, 1894 (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Other Persons -- Benjamin R. Morris -- Letters Received, 1903 (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Other Persons -- Gouverneur Morris -- Letters Received, 1787 (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - Other Persons -- James Morris -- Letters Received, 1819 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Other Persons -- William Newall -- Letters Received, 1905 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Other Persons -- Peter T. O'Brien -- Letters Received, 1876 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Other Persons -- Richard O'Brien -- Letters Received, 1876 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Other Persons -- Mary O'Neal -- Letters Received, 1889 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Other Persons -- William Patterson -- Letters Received, 1868, 1872 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Other Persons -- Annie Pierrepont -- Letters Received, 1842 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Other Persons -- Ann Stuyvesant Pritchard -- Letters Received (w/response), 1708 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Other Persons -- Thomas Pritchard -- Letters Received, 1703, 1705 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Other Persons -- Ramage & Ferguson -- Letters Received, N.D. (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Other Persons -- F. W. Rhinelander -- Letters Received, 1904 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - Other Persons -- Mr. [ ] Rivington -- Letters Received, 1776 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Other Persons -- Francis Russell -- Letters Received, 1866 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Other Persons -- Col. John Scriven -- Letters Received, 1877 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - Other Persons -- G. Sieberg -- Letters Received, 1868 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - Other Persons -- [ ] Steele -- Letters Received, 1895 (Box 21, Folder 43)
  - Other Persons -- Dr. J. G. Thomas -- Letters Received, 1877 (Box 21, Folder 44)
  - Other Persons -- Charles D. Thompson -- Letters Received, 1906 (Box 21, Folder 45)
  - Other Persons -- John [Tilfer] -- Letters Received, 1889 (Box 21, Folder 46)
  - Other Persons -- Elais van Arsdale -- Letters Received, 1840 (Box 21, Folder 47)
  - Other Persons -- Jacob [Rutsen] van Rensselaer -- Letters Received, 1815 (Box 21, Folder 48)
  - Other Persons -- [ ] Watson -- Letters Received, 1899 (Box 21, Folder 49)
  - Other Persons -- G. L. Watson & Co. -- Letters Received, 1901 (Box 21, Folder 50)
  - Other Persons -- Henry White (fl. ca. 1763) -- Letters Received (Box 21, Folder 51)
  - Other Persons -- Charles G. Wier -- Letters Received, 1883 (Box 21, Folder 52)
  - Other Persons -- Benjamin Robert Winthrop -- Letters Received, 1820 (Box 21, Folder 53)
  - Other Persons -- [Chief Engineer of Arcturus (Yacht)] -- Letters Received, 1901 (Box 21, Folder 54)
  - Other Persons -- Miles [Myles] Cooper -- Letters Sent, Recipient Unknown, 1783, 1784 (Box 21, Folder 55)
  - Other Persons -- D. Henon -- Letters Sent, Recipient Unknown, 1867, 1889 (Box 21, Folder 56)
  - Other Persons -- Richard Lawrence -- Letters Sent, Recipient Unknown, 1768 (Box 21, Folder 57)
  - Other Persons -- Egerton Leigh -- Letters Sent, Recipient Unknown, 1781 (Box 21, Folder 58)
  - Other Persons -- Archibald Rutherfurd -- Letters Sent, Recipient Unknown, 1774 (Box 21, Folder 59)
  - Other Persons -- P. C. van Stuyvesant -- Letters Sent, Recipient Unknown, 1801 (Box 21, Folder 60)
  - Other Persons -- [Jun.] Wilmot -- Letters Sent, Recipient Unknown, 1766 (Box 21, Folder 61)
  - Other Persons -- -- A. DeCosson -- Article "Arsenals and Armories of Southern Germany and Austria", 1891 (Box 21, Folder 62)
  - Other Persons/Unknown Persons --Letters Received, N.D., 1842 - 1931 (Box 21, Folder 63)
  - Other Persons -- -- Partial Letters, Recipient Unknown (Box 21, Folder 64)
  - Other Persons -- -- Invitation, Recipient Unknown, N.D. (Box 21, Folder 64)
  - Other Persons/Unknown Persons -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts, N.D., 1700 - 1815 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Other Persons/Unknown Persons -- Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1816 - 1905 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Other Persons/Unknown Persons -- Surveys, N.D. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Other Persons/Unknown Persons -- Legal Papers, N.D., 1714 - 1905 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Other Persons/Unknown Persons -- Oversize Legal Papers, 1724, 1824 - 1829 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Other Persons/Unknown Persons -- Court Papers, N.D., 1732 - 1802 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Notes and Memoranda, N.D., 1725 - 1917 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified Person -- Memorandum Book, 1747, 1781 - 1782 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified Person -- Account Book, 1884 - 1885 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Unidentified Person -- Account Book, 1799 - 1801 (Box 22, Folder 10)
- Series XXII: Govert Loockermans - Correspondence and Papers (in Dutch) N.D., 1647-1700
  Loockermans was a merchant in New Netherland/New York. His relationship to the Stuyvesant family is unclear.
  The material in this series is arranged strictly chronologically, regardless of type. In 1977, Charles Gehring of the New York State Library summarized the content of some of the items in English. The summaries are appended to this finding aid.
  - Govert Loockermans -- Correspondence and Papers (in Dutch) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Govert Loockermans -- Correspondence and Papers (in Dutch), 1647 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Govert Loockermans -- Correspondence and Papers (in Dutch), 1648 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Govert Loockermans -- Correspondence and Papers (in Dutch), 1649 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Govert Loockermans -- Correspondence and Papers (in Dutch), 1650 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Govert Loockermans -- Correspondence and Papers (in Dutch), 1653 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Govert Loockermans -- Correspondence and Papers (in Dutch), 1662 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Govert Loockermans -- Correspondence and Papers (in Dutch), 1671 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Govert Loockermans -- Correspondence and Papers (in Dutch), 1683 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Govert Loockermans -- Correspondence and Papers (in Dutch), 1692 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Govert Loockermans -- Correspondence and Papers (in Dutch), 1699 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Govert Loockermans -- Correspondence and Papers (in Dutch), 1700 (Box 23, Folder 12)
- Other Series
  The remaining material in the collection consists primarily of single-folder series. The items in these series cannot be identified with any specific person or institution, and thus stand alone.
  - Tranquillity Trust Farm -- Map, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Tranquillity Farms -- Construction of Chicken House, 1892 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - [Tranquillity Farms] -- Bounds of Lots (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Tranquillity Farms -- Big Horse Barn -- Inventory, 1897 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - City of New York -- Organizational Chart of NYC Government, 1907 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Colony/State of New York -- Deductions of Title to Various Tracts, N.D., 1699 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Colony/State of New York -- [Abstracts of Census], 1731, 1807 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - State of New Jersey -- Legislation, N.D., 1907 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Clippings -- Game laws of New York and New Jersey, 1903 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - [Metropolitan Museum of Art] -- [Extract from Minutes] -- Tribute to F. W. Rhinelander, [1904] (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art -- Clippings, N.D., 1905, 1930 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Legal Opinions re Yachting and Navigation, 1895 - 1897 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Biles Island Lottery -- Schedule of Prizes, 1771 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Advertisement for Cockfight, 1761 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Regulations of Mrs. Grattan's Boarding House, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Composite Copper Goods Co. -- Private Memorandum (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Recipes, n.D. (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Children's Drawings, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Poetry, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Maps, N.D. (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - [List of Books in Personal Library] (1 of 2), N.D. (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - [List of Books in Personal Library] (2 of 2), N.D. (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Sloop "Success" -- Log Book, 1750 - 1752 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Snow "Jamaica" -- Sailing Orders, 1752 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Religious Notes, N.D. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Business and Visiting Cards (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Christmas Cards -- Recipients Unknown, 1889 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - [Card Game] -- "Magic Numbers", N.D. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Playing Card/Political Advertisement, 178? (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Religious Booklets, N.D. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified Calculations, N.D. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Fabric Samples, [18th Century] (Box 25, Folder 10)